自人类文明伊始，神话与阴谋论便如影随形
Myths and conspiracy theories have always been a thing since man created civilization
它们始终深深吸引着我
and they have always interested me
随着互联网的兴起与论坛文化的诞生
when the internet came around along with the introduction of form culture
这些光怪陆离的信念开始野蛮生长，其传播之势如燎原之火
these outlandish beliefs began growing in number and spreading like never before
可想而知，在21世纪的头十年里
so you can imagine that in the 2000s
无论新旧，各种奇谈甚嚣尘上
we had a grand resurgence of both old and new ones all over the place
几乎遍及你能想象的任何角落
and about anything you can probably think of
我记得，那正是我初次接触这诸多神话的时期
I remember this being a time I was exposed to a lot of these myths,
或是不经意间的邂逅，或是源于内心的好奇
whether it's from random exposure or curiosity.
我相信，不论你们身处哪个网络时代，都曾有过类似的体验
And I'm sure a lot of you, no matter the internet era, have went through the same type of experience.
因此，我想回溯时光，探寻那些曾席卷千禧年代互联网的种种理论
So, I wanted to go back and look at some of the theories that plagued the 2000's internet.
在冰山图视频开始前，请允许我声明，其中绝大多数都是些荒诞不经的奇谈
Let me just preface this iceberg with the fact that most of these are harebrained theories
它们既不代表我的个人观点，也大多与现实世界相去甚远
and don't represent what I think, nor do many of them really align with reality.
许多理论甚至对事件的亲历者构成了极大的不尊重
Many of them are also really disrespectful to those caught in the event, so,
故此，我再次强调，我并不认同这些说法，尤其是那些愈发离奇的部分
once again, I don't agree with these theories, especially the more outlandish ones.
不过，那些相对无伤大雅的倒也无妨，你们往下看便知
The more innocent ones are fine, though. You'll see.
我还特意略过了一个最显而易见的例子
I also left out one of the more obvious ones because,
因为，你懂的，B站有时对某些信息的上传并不友好，就是这么奇怪
well, YouTube doesn't tend to agree with any info being uploaded on it sometimes. It's weird like that.
好了，我们开始吧
Alright, let's start.
千年虫
Y2K Bug
千年虫是一场几乎成为现实的流行恐慌
The Y2K Bug was a widespread theory and almost event
理论声称，在1999年终的午夜钟声敲响，世界迈入2000年1月1日的那一刻
that, at the end of 1999, at midnight, as soon as the world hit January 1, 2000,
所有电脑都将失灵，进而导致现代文明与社会秩序的崩塌
every computer would malfunction, leading to the end of modern civilization and society.
“从税务申报到社会保障
Everything from tax returns to Social Security could be a problem
一旦陈旧的程序拒绝承认21世纪的到来，一切都可能陷入混乱”
if old programming refuses to acknowledge the 21st century.
“‘千年虫’的根源在于此
The source of the year 2000 bug is this.
旧时的计算机程序仅用两位数来存储年份，例如85或97
Older computer programs have a two-digit area to store the year, 85 or 97, for instance.
程序员们想当然地以为年份的前两位永远是19
Computer programmers assumed the first two digits would always be 19,
但随着千禧年的临近
but with the approach of the millennium,
一些计算机会将2000年误判为1900年”
some computers will confuse the year 1900 with the real current year of 2000.
这催生了千年虫恐慌
This birthed the Y2K scare,
企业界普遍认为，修复其所造成的损失将耗资数十亿美元之巨
with companies believing the damages caused would need billions of dollars to fix.
由于大多数人对这个潜在错误的全部后果并不明朗
Due to most not being clarified on the entirety of the potential bug,
许多人开始囤积生活必需品和防护物资，如食物，水，发电机，枪支和现金
many stocked up on essentials and protections like food, water, power generators, firearms, and cash.
然而，这个问题最终以极小的代价被化解
However, the problem was prevented with minimal issue
而那些未受保护的机器也因其损伤微乎其微而招致批评
and the machines that weren't protected were criticized for being barely damaged.
千年虫后遗症
Y2K Hangover
许多人推测，千年虫的实际影响远比我们所看到的要深远
Many theorized that Y2K actually did a lot more than we were shown.
据说该理论的佐证是，全球众多公司为迎接末日
This theory is supposedly supported by the fact that many corporations around the globe
而大量囤积了个人电脑，服务器以及更多设备
stocked up on PCs, servers, and more to prepare for the end.
这个术语也指代千年虫恐慌过后科技行业出现的增长放缓现象
This term also refers to the slowdown in tech work that happened post-Y2K scare.
化学凝结尾
Chemtrails
化学凝结尾理论始于90年代末，并在2000年代愈演愈烈
The Chemtrails theories began in the late 90s and picked up more steam in the 2000s,
这得益于互联网论坛的推波助澜
thanks to internet forums
以及像亚特·贝尔和他1999年的深夜电台节目《咫尺天涯AM》
and late night radio hosts such as Art Bell and his 1999 Coast to Coast AM show.
该理论宣称，飞机留下的凝结尾迹中含有化学及生物制剂
This theory claims that condensation trails are being left by aircrafts containing chemicals and bio-agents.
这些化学物质通常被认为具有恶意，但无人确知它们对普罗大众的具体影响
These chemicals are typically nefarious, but no one knows for sure what they're doing to the general populace.
有人认为其目的是操控天气，进行心理控制
Some believe it's to control the weather, control us psychologically,
管理太阳辐射，用不同的生物变异来测试我们
manage radiation from the sun, test us with different biological changes,
甚至只是为了控制人口数量
or even just control the population count.
光明会与流行音乐
Illuminati and pop music
从愚蠢朋克和Jay-Z的手势，到碧昂丝和蕾哈娜的象征符号
From Daft Punk and Jay Z's hand sign to Beyonce and Rihanna symbolism,
在2000年代，每一位名人似乎都被揣测为精英秘密组织——光明会的成员
in the 2000s every celebrity was theorized to be part of the elite shadow organization, the Illuminati.
该组织的初衷据称是反抗政府的各种影响与滥权，以及迷信和宗教的束缚
The original group's goals were stated to oppose various influences and abuses of government, superstitions, and religion.
尤其是在现代的解读中，人们相信该组织还受到了撒旦教的影响
There is also believed to be a satanic influence in the group, especially in more modern interpretations.
华特·迪士尼的冰冻头颅
Walt Disney's Frozen Head
不知何故，在他去世后流传着一个巨大的谣言
For some reason there was this huge myth after his death
说华特·迪士尼的头颅被冰冻起来，并藏在迪士尼地产的一个秘密保险库里
that Walt Disney's head was frozen and hidden in a secret vault on Disney property.
许多人言之凿凿，说那个保险库就位于迪士尼乐园加勒比海盗游乐设施的下方
Many stated that the vault is beneath the Pirates of the Caribbean ride at Disneyland.
这个谣言在他逝世后不久便开始流传
This myth began shortly after his death
并随着互联网的发展而愈演愈烈，最终成为流行文化中的一个大笑话
and with the growth of the internet blew up even more, becoming a big joke in pop culture.
汽车脚踝切割者
The Car Ankle Slicer
我不知道为何总爱谈论这个，但我想，大概是因为我小时候对此心怀恐惧
I don't know why I always love talking about this, but I think it's because I was scared of it as a kid.
与前一个传说类似，汽车脚踝切割者的故事虽源于2000年代之前
Like the previous myth, the Car Ankle Slicer began before the 2000s,
却因网络上的警示视频和论坛的反复提及而声名大噪
but grew in popularity thanks to internet warning videos and forums constantly bringing it up.
故事描述了一个男人藏在车底，等待着通常是女性的车主返回
It consists of a man hiding underneath the car and waiting for, typically a woman, to return to it.
一旦时机成熟，袭击者便会割开她的脚踝
Once this happens, the assailant slices her ankles,
使其无法行走，然后将她绑架，并通常会开走她的车
leaving her unable to walk while they kidnap her and usually take her car.
新世界秩序
NWO
不，这不是那个摔角组织
No, this isn't the wrestling organization.
这实际上是最流行的传说之一，并且似乎随着代代相传而不断壮大或演变
This is actually one of the most popular myths and only seems to grow and or change with every generation it's passed down to.
“新世界秩序是一种信念，我想，你可以说新世界秩序阴谋论是一种信念
The New World Order is a belief, I guess you'd say the conspiracy theory of the New World Order is a belief that,
它通常由右翼团体所持
on the part of usually right-wing groups, I think,
认为存在一个秘密组织
that there is sort of a secret organization of
或许是联合国之类的机构，计划在整个地球上强加一个世界统一政府”
maybe the United Nations or something like that, that plans to impose kind of a one-world government on the entire planet.
迈克尔·杰克逊之死
The death of Michael Jackson
与许多名人逝世一样，迈克尔·杰克逊的离去也伴随着诸多猜测
Like many celebrity deaths, Michael Jackson's passing was followed by many theories.
尽管迈克尔的死因是摄入致命剂量的麻醉药物
While Michael truthfully passed due to a lethal dose of an anesthetic drug,
但一些人推测他伪造了自己的死亡以求遁世
some theorize that he faked his death to disappear.
有些理论称这是因为盛名所累，也有些说是因为围绕他的争议
Some of these theories state that it was due to the fame, some say it was due to the controversy around him.
但最离奇的说法来自一位所谓特工的爆料
But the oddest one consists of claims from a supposed agent
称迈克尔在一个名为“塞奇威克行动”的阴谋中
that say Michael was made aware of a plot to take him out
扮演了角色后，得知有人要除掉他
after his hand in an alleged plot called Operation Sedgwick,
该计划隶属于罗纳德·里根政府，意图通过音乐来控制非裔美国人群体
which was a plan under Ronald Reagan that would control the African-American population through music.
波利比乌斯
Polybius
这是一个古老的传说，在2000年代爆发，讲述了一款街机游戏
This is an old myth that exploded in the 2000s about a video game cabinet
它会导致玩过的孩子们出现癫痫，噩梦，幻觉和失忆
that would cause children that played to suffer seizures, nightmares, hallucinations, and amnesia.
它还会让玩家沉迷其中
It would also make players into attics for it,
迫使他们反复游玩，直到他们死亡，消失或精神失常
causing them to return to play multiple times until they either passed, vanished, or went crazy.
据说，曾有黑衣人记录下这些玩家的数据
Apparently there were men in black that recorded data on these players
然后将这些机器带走并永远藏匿起来
before taking and hiding the machines forever.
失传剧集
Lost Episodes
当时涌现出大量关于失传剧集的传说
There were a ton of lost episode myths
它们要么完全受到蠕动意面的启发，要么部分源自于此
coming out that were either fully inspired or somewhat came from creepypastas.
就像一场传话游戏，诸如“章鱼哥紫砂”
Like a game of telephone, stories like Squidward's suicide
（我刚才好像打直球了，不要怪我喵）
和“猫和老鼠最后一集”之类的故事四处流传，许多人信以为真
and the Last Tom and Jerry episode went around, and many thought them to be true.
就是汤姆杰瑞失恋卧轨那一集
这些所谓的失传剧集总是对原剧进行黑暗的扭曲
These lost episodes were always dark twists of the featured shows,
而上述两个广为人知的例子，都以角色自我了结告终
with these two popular examples ending with the characters taking their own lives.
奥巴马出生地之谜
Obama birther
出于种族主义的动机，围绕奥巴马2008年的就职典礼产生了大量的传说和理论
Due to racism, there were tons of myths and theories concerning Obama's 2008 inauguration.
其中最著名的是“出生地理论”
One of the most popular is the birther theory,
该理论声称奥巴马并非美国本土出生的公民，因此没有资格竞选总统
which basically says that Obama wasn't eligible to run because he wasn't a natural born citizen of the US.
尽管他实际上出生于夏威夷
While he was actually born in Hawaii,
但该理论坚称他其实出生在肯尼亚，并伪造了一份假的出生证明
the theory states that he was actually born in Kenya, but forged a fake birth certificate.
另一些说法则称他出生于其他国家和地区，但情节大同小异
Others state that he was born in other countries and nations, but each follows the same beats.
艾薇儿·拉维尼
Avril Lavigne
不知何故，在2000年代，一个流传甚广的理论声称，歌手艾薇儿·拉维尼
For some reason in the 2000s, there was a widespread theory about singer Avril Lavigne
已于2003年去世，并由她的替身梅丽莎·范德拉取而代之
being replaced by her body double, Melissa Vandella, after her death in 2003.
尽管这一理论实际上始于2011年
While this theory actually started in 2011,
但我仍觉得有必要将其纳入，因为它与2000年代紧密相连
I felt like I had to include it because of its ties to the 2000s and how it represents
并预示了此后层出不穷的名人死亡骗局
so many celeb death hoaxes to follow.
Xbox 360死亡三红
Xbox 360's Red Ring
许多人相信，Xbox 360的“死亡三红”实际上是蓄意为之
Many believe that the Xbox 360's Red Ring of Death was actually made on purpose
是一项过早启动的计划性报废程序
as an early planned obsolescence program that went off too early.
碧昂丝
Beyonce
碧昂丝的名字点缀着许多疯狂的阴谋论
Beyonce's name decorates many insane conspiracy theories.
其中一个声称她和Jay-Z在光明会中的地位更高
One states that she and Jay are higher ups than the Illuminati.
另一些则说她是恶魔崇拜者，并在歌曲中夹带私货
Others say that she's a devil worshiper and puts messages in her songs.
还有人说她用一个充气肚皮伪造了怀孕
Some say that she also faked her pregnancy with an inflatable stomach.
倒放隐藏信息
Backmasking
说到隐藏信息
Speaking of hidden messages,
其他音乐艺术家也经常被指控在歌曲中通过倒放的方式藏匿信息
other music artists were constantly hit with claims of hidden messages found in their songs via listening backwards.
陷入此类指控的包括姆爷，水果姐，Lady Gaga，碧昂丝等等
Some who were caught in this were Eminem, Katy Perry, Lady Gaga, Beyonce, and many more.
暗网
The Dark Web
由于围绕它的谣言层出不穷，暗网在2000年代堪称舞台中央最恐怖的存在
The Dark Web was honestly center stage as the scariest thing of all time in the 2000s due to the amount of rumors concerning it.
许多都市传说和虚假网站让人们相信，通过暗网可以即时接触到杀手
Many creepypastas and fake sites led many to believe that there was instant access to hitmen,
武器和隐藏的政府文件
weapons, and hidden government files through it.
实际上，那里充斥着胡说八道和更糟糕的，毫无乐趣可言的东西
In reality, it's full of BS and worse things of the not fun variety.
最重要的是，你能在暗网上找到的大部分东西，在表层网络上同样可以找到
This is topped off with the fact that most things you can find on the dark web, you can find on the surface as well.
手机致癌
Cell phones cause cancer
有一个理论曾让我恐惧不已
One theory that used to scare the heck out of me
它声称长时间使用手机最终会导致癌症
was one that alleged that prolonged usage of cell phones will eventually cause cancer.
手机发射的辐射被认为是问题的根源所在
The radiation emitted by cell phones was stated to be the reasoning behind the issue.
然而，事实证明，手机释放的非电离辐射
However, the non-ionizing radiation that cell phones release
强度太弱，不足以损伤DNA并引发癌症
is proven to be too weak to damage the DNA and cause cancer.
电动汽车压制论
Electric Car Suppression
众多理论声称，某些技术和能源正受到压制
Numerous theories claim that certain technologies and energies are being suppressed.
这些理论基于化石燃料公司阻碍电动汽车取得更广泛成功的指控
These theories are based on allegations of the fossil fuel companies holding back electric cars from wider success.
实际上，2006年还上映了一部关于此事的纪录片，名为《谁消灭了电动车？》
There's actually an entire documentary about this that was released in 2006 called Who Killed the Electric Car?
iPod白色耳机
iPod White Earbuds
iPod的问世及其成功之后，紧随而来的是一个由恐惧引发的阴谋论
The iPod released and its success would be followed by a fear-induced conspiracy,
但并非你所预料的那种
but not one that you'd expect.
在2000年代中期iPod大行其道之时
During the iPod's big takeover in the mid-2000s,
据说白色耳机及其线缆是一个明显的标志
it was said that the sight of white earbuds and white cords connected to them would be a dead giveaway
表明某人正随身携带昂贵的设备，从而使他们成为潜在的盗窃目标
that one was walking around with an expensive device, marking them as a potential theft target.
这个理论实际上源于真实事件，当时各大城市发生了相当数量的iPod被盗案件
This theory actually came from real-life events, with there being a good number of iPods being stolen in major cities.
2007年，当旧金山的通勤者们
It was pushed further when in 2007,
收到湾区捷运警察的警告
San Francisco commuters were warned by BART,
提醒他们在乘坐公共交通时警惕iPod盗贼时，这一说法更是甚嚣尘上
Bay Area Rapid Transport Police, that they should watch for iPod thieves when taking the transportation.
这导致各地的iPod用户纷纷隐藏自己的设备
This would lead iPod owners everywhere to hide their devices
并将标志性的白色耳机换成更不起眼的款式
and swap the iconic white headphones for something more generic.
麦克风永久在线
Always on mics
在智能音箱真正开始时刻监听我们之前的许多年
Years before smart speakers actually started always listening to us,
就已经有理论称其他设备的麦克风出于各种原因——
there were theories that mics from other devices were always listening to us
如监视或广告——而始终处于开启状态
for different reasons such as surveillance or just advertising.
微软为Xbox 360推出的Kinect就因此理论而备受审视
Microsoft's Kinect for the Xbox 360 fell under scrutiny for this theory.
许多人相信，该设备永久在线会让微软监视用户，尽管事实并非如此
Many believed the device always being on would have Microsoft spying on users when that didn't end up actually being the case.
有趣的是，关于Kinect的许多强烈反对，实际上源于网络喷子
Funny enough, a lot of the Kinect blowback via this theory actually came from trolls,
理论家，恐慌制造者和玩笑，但这些都导致许多人真正开始担忧自己的隐私
theorists, fear mongers, and jokes that caused many to truly worry about their privacy.
玛丽莲·曼森的肋骨
Marilyn Manson's Ribs
不知为何，曾有传言说曼森为了能够自交而移除了几根肋骨
For some reason there was a myth about Manson getting some ribs removed so he could suck his own meat.
是的，这个话题我们就此打住吧
Yeah, I'll just move on from this one.
E-ZPass追踪
Easy Pass Tracking
E-ZPass基本上就是一种高速公路的非接触式支付系统
Easy Pass is basically contactless payment for tolls.
无需停车缴费或等待邮寄账单
Instead of stopping to pay or waiting for a letter in the mail to pay,
你的账户会在通过收费站或使用E-ZPass车道时通过RFID技术自动扣款
your account uses RFID to take the amount from your account when passing a booth or taking an Easy Pass route.
然而，许多人很快开始担忧隐私问题
However, many quickly became concerned with privacy
因为E-ZPass虽声称仅用于计费，却能轻易地被用来追踪用户行踪
as Easy Pass, while said to simply be used for billing, could easily be used to track subscribers.
不过，当你意识到如今我们几乎被强制要求
However, this is somewhat moot
不带手机寸步难行说是
随身携带一个时刻在线的追踪器时，这种担忧似乎就有些多余了
when you realize we're basically required to own a constantly online tracker these days.
乔治·W·布什的服役争议
George W. Bush Service Controversy
在他2004年的总统竞选期间
During his 2004 presidential run,
出现了一种理论，声称布什并未真正服役于国民警卫队
a theory emerged that alleged that Bush didn't actually serve in the National Guard.
该理论指出，由于其家族背景，布什得到了优待，从而得以避免战斗任务
The theory states that due to his family, Bush was given a sugar-coated treatment, allowing him to avoid combat service.
其中一部分原因是他缺席了飞行员培训
A part of this comes from his absence from pilot training,
导致无法加入F-102战斗机飞行员计划
resulting in an inability to join the F-102 pilot program.
许多此类信息来源于现已被证伪的“基利安文件”
A lot of this info comes from the now debunked Killian documents,
那是一组包含六份文件的集合，内容是关于
which is a collection of six documents containing false allegations
布什在德州空军国民警卫队服役的虚假指控
about Bush's Texas Air National Guard service.
蜡烛湾
Candle Cove.
在2000年代，ARG的创作者们一个非常流行的消遣
A very popular internet pastime for ARG creators in the 2000s
就是创建关于虚构的失传媒体和恐怖故事的论坛
was creating forums about made-up lost media and creepy stories.
其中一个大名鼎鼎的便是《蜡烛湾》，一个从未存在过的恐怖儿童节目
A big one was Candle Cove, which is a creepy kids show that never existed.
节目中充满了诡异的木偶，潜意识信息等等
The show is full of creepy puppets, subliminal messages, and more.
其叙事方式是通过多个论坛帖子
The method of telling it was multiple forum posts,
人们仿佛亲身经历般地谈论着他们对这部失传剧集的记忆
speaking on elements they remember from this lost show as if it was real.
虽然这显然是一个蠕动意面，但与许多网络传说一样
While this was obviously a creepypasta, as with many internet myths,
它源于一个被过度解读或误解的恐怖故事
it came from a horror story being taken too seriously or misconstrued.
查克芝士的披萨
Chuck E. Cheese Pizza.
2000年代流传着一个怪诞的理论，说的是查克芝士餐厅打烊后
There's this weird 2000s theory about how after the restaurant closes,
员工会把客人吃剩的披萨重新拼凑成一个完整的披萨
Chuck E. Cheese employees take the leftover uneaten pizzas and put them back together into a full pizza.
我读到这时一直在强忍着不笑出声来
I was trying not to laugh the whole time I was reading that.
不过嘛，我猜也行吧，我的意思是
But, sure, I guess. I mean,
比起重新烤一张饼，费力去缝合一个科学怪人般的披萨似乎更麻烦
I think it'd be more work to stitch together a Frankenstein pizza over just cooking a new pie.
噶腰子邮件
Kidney Heist Email.
在90年代到2000年代，流传着一个故事
In the 90s through 2000s, a story was passed around
讲述了一个流行的阴谋论，即有人在冰浴缸中醒来，发现自己少了一个肾
entailing a popular conspiracy that there were people waking up in ice tubs with a missing kidney.
这个故事通过电子邮件传播
It was spread by email that
通常以主人公独自旅行，最终在所述的浴缸中醒来为开端
typically began with the person traveling alone until they woke up in said tub.
信息中最令人难忘的部分大致如下
The most memorable part of the message would follow similarly to this.
墙上贴着一张纸条，上面写着，“想活命就打911”
There's a note taped to the wall saying, call 911 if you want to live.
艾伦拨打了911，接线员让他摸摸自己的后背
Alan calls 911 and the operator asks him to touch his back.
艾伦伸手到背后，感觉到下背部有一道长长的疤痕
Alan reaches behind him and feels a long scar down his lower back.
有人对他进行了一场粗糙的手术
Someone had done a crude surgery on him,
摘走了他的肝脏，并很可能在黑市上卖了个好价钱
removing his liver, which they presumably sold on the black market for a lot of money.
我知道我说的是噶腰子邮件，但有时候他们连肝脏也不放过
I know I said Kidney Heist email, but sometimes they'll take the liver too.
你知道，他们偷器官的时候，大概是不挑的
You know, they're not picky with the organ they're stealing, I guess.
波希米亚格罗夫
Bohemian Grove.
2000年7月15日，亚历克斯·琼斯和摄影师迈克·汉森潜入了波希米亚格罗夫
On July 15th, 2000, Alex Jones and cameraman Mike Hansun would enter the Bohemian Grove,
一个占地2700英亩的营地
a 2,700-acre campground
隶属于一个名为波希米亚俱乐部的私人绅士俱乐部
belonging to a private gentleman's club, the Bohemian Club,
并记录下了“关怀火葬”仪式
and record the cremation of care ceremony.
琼斯错误地将该事件标记为一场献祭
Jones would falsely flag the event as a sacrifice
而那段录像也导致他和其他人将该组织称为一个举行撒旦仪式的影子精英团体
and that footage would lead, he and others, to call the group a shadow elite performing satanic rituals.
这一信念随之传播，各种理论纷纷涌现
This belief would spread with theories appearing
声称该组织正被用来引领精英阶层建立一个新世界秩序
claiming that the group is being used to pilot the elite into a new world order.
预测性编程
Predictive Programming
有阴谋论者认为，某次2001年的事件是一场内部阴谋
There are conspiracy theories that believe that a certain 2001 event was an inside job
并整理了2001年前流行文化中的种种迹象，据称这些迹象预示了该事件的发生
and have cataloged pre-2001 pop culture signs that allegedly foreshadowed it.
这些迹象被视为精英阶层参与此事的证据
These signs stand as evidence that the elite were in on the event
并出现在电影，电视节目，甚至建筑符号中
and are seen in films, TV shows, and even architectural symbols.
显然，这种编程甚至可以追溯到50年代的蜘蛛侠
Apparently, this programming goes back to even the 50s with Spider-Man,
芝麻街，神奇女侠，兔八哥等作品中
Sesame Street, Wonder Woman, Looney Tunes, and more.
伪旗事件
False Flag Events
2000年代充斥着各种伪旗理论
The 2000s were full of false flag theories,
这些理论声称存在秘密的政府行动，旨在将某些行为嫁祸于非政府组织
which are alleged covert government operations made to look like non-aligned groups committed to acts.
理论家们将此标签附着的事件数量之多
The instances that theorists attach this to are so numerous
显而易见这只是为了迎合某种议程而进行的随意牵强附会
that it's obvious it's just a random pull to fit an agenda.
北美共同货币
The Amero
2001年，有人推测，一个涵盖美国
In 2001, it was theorized that there would be a new currency
加拿大和墨西哥的地区将会出现一种名为“Amero”的新货币
in the area encompassing the US, Canada, and Mexico called the Amero.
许多人认为这是我们货币单位发展的必然趋势，但此事显然毫无下文
As many thought as a necessary evolution of our monetary unit, this obviously went nowhere.
乔氏超市的停车场
Trader Joe's Parking
如果你去过那家时髦的杂货店——乔氏超市
If you've ever been to the hipster grocery store, Trader Joe's,
你会很快注意到它的停车场总是这副模样
you'll quickly notice that the parking lot always looks like this.
抱歉，这类理论总让我忍俊不禁
I'm sorry. The theories like this crack me up.
他们的停车场对于顾客数量来说总是显得太小
That constant feeling of their lots being too small for the shopper base
这催生了一个理论
actually created a theory
即他们的停车场是故意设计得很小，以便看起来总是人满为患
that its parking lots are small on purpose so they look packed and busy all the time.
老实说，我倒觉得是有人太吝啬或太愚蠢，没意识到喜欢乔氏超市的人真的很多
Honestly, I thought someone was just too cheap or stupid to actually realize that a lot of people like Trader Joe's.
布兰妮·斯皮尔斯是间谍
Britney Spears is a Spy
不知何故，有传言称布兰妮·斯皮尔斯受雇于布什政府
For some reason, it's alleged that Britney Spears was hired by the Bush administration
哎呦我，我差点又笑出来了
Oh my god, I almost laughed again.
在伊拉克战争之后，每当布什政府爆出丑闻，她就会制造事端以分散公众注意力
Following the Iraq war in order to get into scandals and cause a distraction whenever a scandal surrounding the Bush administration occurred.
听着，别信这些，别信这些东西
Listen, don't believe this. Don't believe this stuff.
激浪中的柠檬黄5号
Mountain Dew Yellow Five
一个极受欢迎的谣言，在网上出现后，主要通过校园内的口耳相传而散播
There was a super popular myth spread mostly by word of mouth in schools after surfacing on the net
声称喝激浪会杀死精子，减少精子数量
concerning Mountain Dew killing sperm cells, reducing your count.
这归咎于其中使用的咖啡因和柠檬黄5号染料
This was due to its usage of caffeine and yellow dye five.
真正的问题是，为什么一群在校学生会关心精子细胞的损失
The real question is why a bunch of school kids cared about losing sperm cells
好像他们马上就要用上似的
like they were about to use them anytime soon.
新可乐
New Coke
有一种理论声称，可口可乐公司在80年代推出新可乐
There's a theory that claims that the Coca-Cola company changed to a worse formula with New Coke
并让其存续至2002年
after it dropped in the 80s and lived to 2002
是为了改用更差的配方，以此来推高原版产品的需求
in order to drive up demand for the original product
或是在重新推出原版时得以使用更廉价的原料
or permit the reintroduction of an original with a new formula using cheaper ingredients.
气象控制
Weather Control
许多理论认为，政府掌握着控制天气的工具
There are many theories that believe that governments have access to weather controlling tools.
是真的，我亲眼看见哈夫克在风暴眼这个地方使用过
其中之一便是已被证伪的说法
One includes the debunked belief that HAARP,
即高频主动极光研究计划（HAARP）
the High Frequency Active Auroral Research Program,
一个由美国政府资助的无线电技术研究项目
a radio technology research program funded by the U.S. government,
实际上是一个秘密的气象控制系统
is a secret weather controlling system.
炭疽信件
Anthrax Letters
炭疽信件案指的是含有炭疽杆菌孢子的信件
The anthrax letter case entailed letters containing anthrax spores
被邮寄至媒体机构和美国参议院办公室，导致5人死亡，17人感染
being mailed to media outlets and U.S. Senate offices, resulting in five passings and 17 infections.
美国微生物学家，生物防御研究员和疫苗学家布鲁斯·埃文斯被认定为罪魁祸首
American microbiologist, biodefense researcher, and vaccinologist Bruce Evans was found to be the perpetrator.
然而，阴谋论者们相信这是一种掩盖，目的是让埃文斯噤声
However, the conspiracists believed that this was a cover-up to silence Evans
以隐藏其背后的牵连
to hide its involvement.
零售业RFID
Retail RFID
RFID，即射频识别技术
RFID, or radio frequency identification,
通常用于自动追踪和识别商店中的物品
is typically used to automatically track and ID items in stores,
实现非接触式卡支付，宠物微芯片植入以及更多功能
allow for contactless card payments, pet microchipping, and a lot more.
然而，在2006年，一些基督教千禧年末世论者推测
However, in 2006, some Christian millennialists
RFID是“野兽的印记”，意味着这是末日来临的征兆
theorized that RFID was the mark of the beast, meaning that it was a sign of the end times.
作家兼消费者权益倡导者凯瑟琳·阿尔布雷希特
Catherine Albrecht, writer and consumer advocate,
通过她的著作
brought this to the attention of the world with her book,
《间谍芯片的威胁：为何基督徒应抵制RFID与电子监控》将此问题公之于众
The Spy Chips Threat, Why Christians Should Resist RFID and Electronic Surveillance.
该书论述了公司，政府等机构将如何利用RFID来追踪商品和人员
The book speaks on how using RFID, companies, the government, and more, would track goods and people.
不仅如此，阿尔布雷希特还声称，RFID芯片，特别是Verichip
Not only this, but Albrecht claims that RFID chips, namely the Verichip,
与《圣经·启示录》中描述的印记相似，而《启示录》正是描绘末世景象的篇章
resembles the mark, as described in the Bible's Book of Revelation, which details the end times.
根据2006年《连线》杂志一篇关于该理论的文章
According to a Wired article on a theory from 2006,
阿尔布雷希特指出，如果Verichip成为一种普遍的支付设备
Albrecht states that if the Verichip becomes a common payment device,
类似于埃克森美孚SpeedPass中的非接触式支付系统
similar to the contactless payment system in the Exxonmobil Speedpass,
所有希望买卖商品的人都将被迫在右手或额头上接受一个印记
All who wish to buy and sell goods will be compelled to receive a mark on their right hand or foreheads,
正如《启示录》中所言
as it says in Revelation.
据波士顿大学教授理查德·兰德斯所说
According to Boston University professor Richard Landis,
在此之前已经有过许多类似的理论，包括围绕千年虫，条形码和社保号码的理论
there are many similar theories that came before this one, including ones based around Y2K, barcodes, and social security numbers.
死亡小组理论
Death panel theory
死亡小组理论是一个与巴拉克·奥巴马有关，已被深度证伪的理论
Death panel theory is a deeper debunked theory relating to Barack Obama.
它声称他的医疗保健法案将设立“死亡小组”
It claimed that his healthcare legislation would create death panels
来为老年人和残疾人决定临终关怀事宜
to make decisions about end-of-life care for the elderly and disabled.
据说，此事始于前阿拉斯加州长萨拉·佩林在Facebook上的一篇帖子
It's stated to have began with a Facebook post from former Alaska Governor Sarah Palin,
她在其中声称《平价医疗法案》
where she claimed the Affordable Care Act
将强制设立死亡小组，以决定哪些美国人应该生，哪些应该死
would mandate death panels to decide which Americans should live or die.
令人意外的是，新闻媒体试图纠正这一信息
News media would surprisingly attempt to rectify and correct this information, b
但“死亡小组”一词的不断使用
ut the constant usage of the term death panels
却分散了人们的注意力，使其作为时代的一大理论愈演愈烈
would distract from it, spurting it even further as a theory of the age.
语音入颅技术
Voice to skull technology
语音入颅，或称V2K
Voice to skull or V2K
是一个与那些相信自己是未来主义电子骚扰受害者的人相关的术语
is a term relating to people that believe they are victims of a futuristic form of electronic harassment,
通常包括脑控
typically which includes mind control.
你是不是有妄想症
Are you delusional?
你实际上能听到脑海里的声音，这是因为微波作为载波段加热了颞叶
You could actually hear voices in your head from microwave being the carrier band heating up the temporal lobes.
他们相信有第三方正利用微波听觉效应，将声音，思想
They believe a third party is using the microwave auditory effect to transmit voices, thoughts,
或潜意识信息传输到他们的脑海中
and or subliminal messages into their minds.
我们将在最后一层部分对此进行更详细的阐述
We'll expand on this more with the part of the final layer.
读博的时间旅行者
Gambling Time Travelers
始于一个播客玩笑
Beginning as a podcast joke,
一个谣言开始流传，称美国的强力球彩票是为了捕捉时间旅行者而设立的
a myth began to spread around that the Powerball Lottery in the US was created to catch time travelers.
彩票不该有防穿越机制吗
该信念认为，一个未来的时间旅行者会回到过去，购买并赢得彩票
The belief goes that a future time traveler would come back to play and win the lottery.
他们将被捕获并被审问其所掌握的技术
They would be captured and interrogated about their technology.
尼比鲁行星
Planet Nibiru
一些阴谋论者相信，诸如NASA之类的组织
Some conspiracy theorists believe that there is a plot by organizations such as NASA
正密谋隐瞒太阳系中一颗巨大行星的存在，它被称为尼比鲁或X行星
to conceal the existence of a large planet in the solar system known as Nibiru or Planet X.
他们声称，这颗行星将近距离掠过地球，并将其摧毁
They state that this planet will pass close enough to the Earth to destroy it.
预测的毁灭日期包括2003年，2012年和2017年
Predictions for the date of destruction have included 2003, 2012, and 2017.
蓝光计划
Project Bluebeam
蓝光计划阴谋论由加拿大记者
Popularized in the mid-90s and growing in the 2000s,
塞尔日·莫纳斯特于90年代中期提出，并在2000年代广为流传
the Project Bluebeam conspiracy was created by Canadian journalist Sergey Manast.
该理论基于这样的指控：全球精英计划伪造一场外星人入侵
This theory is based around allegations that the global elites plan
其目的，你猜对了，就是为了建立新世界秩序
to fake an alien invasion in order to, you guessed it, create the New World Order.
以色列动物间谍
Israel Animal Spies
在2000年代及以后，网上涌现出大量的动物阴谋论
There are tons of animal conspiracies that showed up online during the 2000s and beyond.
据称，以色列曾利用鸟类，海豚和蜥蜴作为间谍
It's alleged that the nation of Israel has used birds, dolphins, and lizards as spies,
遥控鲨鱼进行攻击，并用猪来破坏土地
remote control attack sharks, and pigs to destroy land.
这些传言和指控的时间跨度从2000年代末到2010年代，至今尚未被证实
These myths and allegations range from the late 2000s to 2010s and have yet to be proven right.
有组织纠缠
Organized Gang Stalking
“有组织纠缠”一词于2000年代被创造出来
The term Gang Stalking would be coined in the 2000s,
指的是多人组织起来对单一目标进行跟踪和骚扰
which entails multiple people organizing to stalk and harass a single individual.
此事的阴谋论版本则围绕着身份不明的特工，对受害者进行近乎无限的监视
The conspiracy theory version of this circulates around unknown agents with near unlimited surveillance of the victim,
并以专业级的协调能力，秘密使用技术武器和精神控制手段
covertly with professional level coordination, using technological weapons and mind control.
受害者通常认为，这是政府，影子政府或类似国家行为者的杰作
The victims typically believe that this is the work of a government, shadow government, or similar state actors.
根据法医精神病学研究所的一篇文章
According to an article by the Forensic Psychiatry Institute,
据报道，攻击是通过化学武器，能量武器
the attacks are reported to be done via chemical weapons, energy weapons,
定向噪音，语音入颅设备和被盗器官进行的
targeted noise, voice to school devices, and stolen organs.
文章还指出，受害者报告的信念涉及GPS
It also states that the victims report beliefs of GPS,
电信，无线电频率，人工智能以及社交媒体和金融账户的黑客攻击
telecommunications, radio frequencies, artificial intelligence, and social media and financial account hacking.
黑色直升机
Black helicopters
一个源于70年代的理论，在90年代和2000年代进一步发酵
A 70s holdover theory that blew up further in the 90s and 2000s i
那就是黑色直升机的传说
s that of the black helicopters.
这个阴谋论最初与UFO和牛只肢解的目击事件相关联
This conspiracy began with being linked to UFO and catamulation sightings
并在90年代因美国民兵运动人物声称
and got larger in the 90s due to American militia movement figures
一支联合国部队将乘坐黑色直升机抵达美国进行接管而愈演愈烈
stating a UN force would arrive in the US via black helicopters to take over.
这将成为，是的，又是它，新世界秩序的关键组成部分
This would go to be a key part of the, yeah, again, New World Order.
我感觉自己就像那个神经质的克罗克老师一样，高喊着，新世界秩序！
I feel like freakin' Crocker saying it, New World Order!
我真该学着《反斗家族》里的样子来表演一下
I feel like I should do, like, the fairy-eyed parents thing with that.
但这将导致对那些不愿加入的人使用精神控制技术和集中营
But it would result in the use of mind control tech and concentration camps for those not willing to join.
时间立方
Time Cube
1997年，奥蒂斯·尤金·雷发布了一个名为“时间立方”的理论
In 97, oldest Eugene Ray would release a theory called Time Cube,
它声称地球的一次自转实际上创造了四个同时发生的“天”
and it claims that a single rotation of the earth actually creates four simultaneously occurring days.
他以此证明现代科学的错误，并指责教育工作者是隐藏真相的全球阴谋的一部分
Proving modern science wrong and accusing educators as a part of a global conspiracy to hide the truth.
这一切都发表在雷现已关闭的网站上，虽然无人将其当真
This was all published to Ray's now defunct website and while no one took it seriously,
但它却成了一个著名的网络理论
it became a famous random internet theory
并展示了互联网上的阴谋论兔子洞能有多深
and an example of how deep the conspiracy rabbit hole can go on the internet.
当心牛类
Beware the bovines
“当心牛类”是一个非常奇特的理论，于2003年出现在网络上
Beware the bovines is a very odd theory that appeared on the net in 2003.
这个长篇的单页网站
This long-form, single-page website
详细阐述了一个闻所未闻的阴谋论，即牛类正秘密策划对人类进行大规模毁灭
details an unheard-of conspiracy about how cows secretly plot to commit mass destruction of humans.
通篇都是对读者的警告，告诫他们应如何为这场战斗做准备
Throughout, there are many warnings to readers about how they should prepare for the battle.
作者谈及了人类将需要面对的不同类型的牛类冲突
The writer speaks on the different types of cow clashes that humanity will need to face
甚至警告说，此刻就有监视牛在盯着你
and even warns that there are surveillance cows watching you right now.
几乎可以肯定，这个网站和理论都只是个玩笑
It's almost certain that this site and theory are a joke,
但回顾我们刚才讨论过的那些光怪陆离的奇谈
but with how many weird theories that I just went over with you,
究竟真相如何，还是留给各位自行判断吧
I'll leave that up to you to decide.
非常感谢你们观看和聆听这些胡言乱语
Thank you so much for watching and listening to this nonsense.
制作这样的冰山视频耗时良久，所以如果你能点赞，评论和关注，我不胜感激
These icebergs take forever to put together, so I'd be very thankful if you'd like, comment, and subscribe.
我非常想听听大家对其中一些理论的想法，甚至是亲身经历
I'd really love to hear all you guys' thoughts and even experiences with some of these.
敬请期待，祝你过得愉快
Stay tuned and please have a good one.
Stay tuned and see you next time.